Register of the Boutros Boutros-Ghali papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Secretary-General of the United Nations File, 1981-2001 (Boxes 62-202)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Boxes 148-153)
    - Biegman, Nicholas H., 1996 (Box-folder 152: 20)
    - Biya, Jeanne Irène, 1992 (Box-folder 152: 21)
      From Leia Boutros-Ghali.
    - Blix, Hans, 1994 (Box-folder 152: 22)
    - Borchgrave, Arnaud de, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 152: 23)
    - Bruzonsky, Mark, 1996 (Box-folder 152: 24)
    - Bush, George H., 1991-1993 (Box-folder 152: 25)
      Includes a photocopy of a letter from George H. Bush to Ardeshir Zahedi.
    - Camdessus, Michel, 1993, 1996 (Box-folder 152: 26)
    - Cardoso, Fernando Henrique, undated (Box-folder 152: 27)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 152: 28)
    - Chien, Fred (Minister of Foreign Affairs, Taiwan), 1993 (Box-folder 152: 29)
    - Christopher, Warren, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 152: 30)
    - Claes, Willy, 1995 (Box-folder 152: 31)
    - Clinton, William J., 1993, 1996 (Box-folder 152: 32)
    - Cook, Frances D., 1996 (Box-folder 152: 33)
    - Cot, Jean, 1994 (Box-folder 152: 34)
    - Couteaux, Paul-Marie, 1993 (Box-folder 152: 35)
    - Cristiani-Burkard, Alfredo Félix (Box-folder 152: 36)
    - Das, Siba Kumar, 1995 (Box-folder 152: 37)
    - Dejammet, Alain, 1995 (Box-folder 152: 38)
    - Dole, Bob, 1992 (Box-folder 152: 39)
    - Druon, Maurice, 1993 (Box-folder 152: 40)
    - Dupuy, René-Jean, 1992 (Box-folder 152: 41)
    - Eilts, Hermann Frederick, 1993 (Box-folder 152: 42)
    - England, J. K. Robert, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 1)
    - Erdös, André, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 2)
    - Filali, Abdellatif, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 3)
    - Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 4)
    - Fortune magazine (James B. Hayes), 1993 (Box-folder 153: 5)
    - Freitas Do Amaral, Diogo (Box-folder 153: 6)
    - Fujimori, Alberto Fujimori, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 7)
    - Gilman, Ben, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 8)
    - Giuliani, Rudolph W., 1996 (Box-folder 153: 9)
    - Gorse, Georges, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 10)
    - Hamilton, Lee H., 1995 (Box-folder 153: 11)
    - Hillard, Earl F., 1996 (Box-folder 153: 12)
    - Holbrooke, Richard, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 13)
    - Howard, Michael, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 14)
    - H'un Saen (Hun Sen), 1993 (Box-folder 153: 15)
      Includes declaration of the state of Cambodia.
    - InterAction Council, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 16)
    - Jesus, Jose Luis, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 17)
    - John Paul II, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 18)
    - Karadzic, Radovan, 1994 (Box-folder 153: 19)
    - Kallas, Siim, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 20)
    - Keating, Colin, 1994 (Box-folder 153: 21)
    - Kelman, Herbert C., 1993 (Box-folder 153: 22)
    - Kennedy, Edward M., 1993 (Box-folder 153: 23)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1992, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 24)
    - Klerk, F. W. De, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 25)
    - Koch, Edward I., 1993 (Box-folder 153: 26)
    - Liu Ansheng, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 27)
    - Lord, Winston, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 28)
    - Lowi, Miriam, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 29)
    - Ly, Pierre, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 30)
    - Major, John, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 31)
    - Mérimée, Jean-Bernard, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 32)
    - Mugabe, Robert G., 1996 (Box-folder 153: 33)
    - Muthaura, Francis K., 1995 (Box-folder 153: 34)
    - Najibullah, Fatana, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 35)
    - Noor, Queen of Jordan, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 36)
    - Ould-Abdullah, A., 1994 (Box-folder 153: 37)
    - Pasqua, Charles, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 38)
    - Peng, Li, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 39)
    - Perkins, Edward J., 1992 (Box-folder 153: 40)
    - Piriz-Ballon, Ramiro, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 41)
    - Ranariddh, Norodom, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 42)
    - Reiff, Daniel D., 1996 (Box-folder 153: 43)
    - Reyn, Alex, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 44)
    - Roberts, Adam, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 45)
    - Robinson, James D., III, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 46)
    - Said al-Sahaf, Mohammed, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 47)
    - Salem Sabah Al Salem Al-Sabah, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 48)
    - Salim, Salim Ahmed (Box-folder 153: 49)
    - Sardenberg, Ronaldo Mota, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 50)
    - Shore, Herbert, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 51)
    - Sihanouk, Norodom, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 52)
    - Simon, Paul, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 153: 53)
    - Soros, George, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 54)
    - Strong, Maurice F., 1996 (Box-folder 153: 55)
    - Suzuki, Shunichi, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 56)
    - Tudjman, Franjo, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 57)
    - United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) (Carol Bellamy), 1993-1995 (Box-folder 153: 58)
    - United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) (James Gustave Speth and William Draper III), 1993-1994 (Box-folder 153: 59)
    - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) (Federico Mayor), 1996 (Box-folder 153: 60)
    - United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine and Refugees in the Near East, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 61)
    - Uniao Nacional Para Independencia Total de Angola, 1996 (Box-folder 153: 62)
    - United Ethiopians Democratic Congress, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 63)
    - Unsoeld, J., 1993 (Box-folder 153: 64)
    - Vianello-Chiodo, Marco, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 65)
    - Vorontsoc, Yuliy, 1994 (Box-folder 153: 66)
    - Walters, Barbara, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 153: 67)
    - Weizsäcker, Richard von, 1992 (Box-folder 153: 68)
    - Whitehead, John, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 153: 69)
    - Wishnumurti, Nugroho, 1995 (Box-folder 153: 70)
    - Wiznitzer, Louis, circa 1992 (Box-folder 153: 71)
    - World Bank (James Wolfensohn), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 153: 72)
    - World Affairs Council (J. Curtis Mack), 1995 (Box-folder 153: 73)
    - Wörner, Manfred, 1994 (Box-folder 153: 74)
      Includes letter approving NATO air strikes in Sarajevo.
    - Yeltsin, Boris N., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 153: 75)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 153: 76-77)
  - Finances and budget, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 154: 1)
    See also: Charles Hill Advising and Projects File/Finances and budget documents (Joseph E. Connor).
  - General Assembly
    - Lists of speakers of general debate (Box-folder 154: 2)
    - Lists of dignitaries at 47th, 49th, 50th, and 51st sessions, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 154: 3)
    - Effective Planning, Budgeting and Administration of Peace Keeping Operations, GA 48-218B, 1994 June (Box-folder 154: 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 154: 5)
  - Geographical files (Boxes 154-165)
    Binders of correspondence, reports, resolutions, memoranda, and printed matter on different geographical areas. Includes originals and photocopies.
    - Burundi I, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 154: 6-8)
    - Burundi II, 1996 (Box-folder 155: 1)
    - Cyprus (Box-folder 155: 2)
      Background notes.
    - Eritrea/Yemen, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 155: 3)
    - Iraq
      - Oil-for-Food Talks (Security Council Resolution 986), 1996 (Box-folder 155: 4-5, Box-folder 156: 1-2)
      - Non-paper, "Memorandum of Understanding Between the Secretariat of the United Nations and the Government of Iraq on the Implementation of Security Council Resolution 986 (1995),", 1996 April (Box-folder 156: 3)
    - Libya
      - Binder, "Report of envoys / non-paper / legal office / 'The Three' / Libya-Belgium / Libya-Malta / Libya-France / Libya-U.S. / Libya-United Kingdom / Libya-Secretary General / United Kingdom-Secretary General / Libya-Egypt / Libya-Iran,", 1992-1995 (Box-folder 156: 4-6)
      - Correspondence from Libya to the Secretary-General, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 156: 7, Box-folder 157: 1-3)
        Includes letters from Muammar Qaddafi.
      - Correspondence from the Secretary-General to Libya, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 157: 4)
      - Correspondence from Libya to the Secretary-General, 1993 (Box-folder 157: 5)
      - Correspondence, League of Arab States, 1992 (Box-folder 157: 6)
      - Correspondence, general, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 157: 7)
      - Correspondence, International Court of Justice, 1992 (Box-folder 158: 1)
      - Resolutions, reports, notes for the Secretary-General, and sanctions review, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 158: 2-3)
    - Middle East I, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 158: 4-5)
    - Middle East II, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 159: 1-2)
    - Nigeria I, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 159: 3)
    - Nigeria II, 1996 (Box-folder 159: 4-5)
    - Rwanda I, 1993 (Box-folder 160: 1)
    - Rwanda II, 1994 (Box-folder 160: 2-3)
    - Rwanda III, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 160: 4, Box-folder 161: 1)
    - Rwanda IV, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 161: 2)
    - Somalia I, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 161: 3-5)
    - Somalia II, 1993 (Box-folder 162: 1-3)
    - Somalia III, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 162: 4-5, Box-folder 163: 1)
    - Somalia IV (Task Force file), 1992-1993 (Box-folder 163: 2-4)
    - Western Sahara, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 163: 5-6)
    - Yugoslavia I, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 164: 1)
    - Yugoslavia II, 1994 (Box-folder 164: 2-3)
    - Yugoslavia III, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 164: 4, Box-folder 165: 1-3)
    - Zaire, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 165: 4-5)
    - Additional file on Iraq/Nigeria-Cameroon/Eastern Slovenia/Qana, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 165: 6)
  - Interviews, 1991-1996 and undated (Box-folder 166: 1-7)
  - Meetings and telephone conversations, notes
    Memcons and telcons.
    - 1992 (Box-folder 166: 8)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 166: 9)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 166: 10-13)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 166: 14)
    - Lord Peter Carrington, 1992 July 2 and July 9 (Box-folder 166: 15)
    - Warren Christopher, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 166: 16-17)
      Includes notes from meeting on November 8, 1993 with Christopher and Albright.
    - Jiang Zemin, 1994 (Box-folder 167: 1)
    - Lee Teng-hui, undated (Box-folder 167: 2)
    - Joint meetings on Cyprus, 1992 (Box-folder 167: 3)
    - Delegation of Experts from the Human Rights Program, 1993 (Box-folder 167: 4)
    - Meeting of the Secretary-General with the heads of the World Bank, International Monetary Fund, and World Trade Organization, 1995 (Box-folder 167: 5)
    - Task Force on United Nations Operations, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 167: 6-9)
    - UN Security Council, miscellaneous, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 167: 10)
  - Memoranda, interoffice
  - Notes on the United Nations and democracy, undated (Box-folder 168: 1)
  - Photographs
    - Leia Boutros-Ghali seated with other women, undated (Box-folder 168: 2)
    - Leia Boutros-Ghali with Rudy Giuliani, 1995 September (Box-folder 168: 3)
    - Boutros Boutros-Ghali at UN press conference, 1992 (Box-folder 168: 4)
    - Charles Hill with Caroline Lombardo and Bettina Polydor, 1996 December (Box-folder 168: 5)
    - Heads of state at UN 50 (Oversize-box 289)
  - Press releases
    - 1992 (Box-folder 168: 6)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 168: 7)
      On meeting with Shimon Peres.
    - 1994 (Box-folder 168: 8)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 168: 9)
    - 1995 April-December (Box-folder 168: 10)
      Statements issued by the spokesman for the Secretary-General.
    - 1996 January-October (Box-folder 168: 11)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 168: 12)
  - Printed materials, miscellaneous (Boxes 168-170)
    - Magazines with articles on Boutros Boutros-Ghali (Box-folder 168: 13-15)
    - Foreign Policy Bulletin, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 169: 1-3)
    - Secretariat News, 1992 February (Box-folder 169: 4)
    - "The Expanding Role of the United Nations and Its Implications for United Kingdom Policy," Foreign Affairs Committee, volume I, 1993 June (Box-folder 169: 5)
    - UN Chronicle, 1992 June (Box-folder 169: 6)
    - VN Forum, 1993 (Box-folder 169: 7)
    - Review of International Affairs, vol. XLIII, 1992 (Box-folder 169: 8)
    - Our Global Neighborhood, Report of the Commission on Global Governance, 1995 (Box-folder 169: 9)
    - "A World of Dispute: A Survey of the Frontiers of Development Cooperation,", 1993 (Box-folder 169: 10)
    - Erskine Childers and Brian Urquhart, "Renewing the United Nations System," Development Dialogue, 1994 (Box-folder 170: 1)
    - "The UN in Crisis," Foreign Policy, 1995 (Box-folder 170: 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 170: 3-4)
  - Reports (Boxes 170-171)
    - Report of the Secretary-General on the Work of the Organization
      Printed copies.
      - 1991 (Box-folder 170: 5)
        By Javier Pérez de Cuéllar.
      - 1992 September (Box-folder 170: 6)
      - 1993 September (Box-folder 170: 7)
      - Photocopies of 1992-1993 reports (Box-folder 170: 8)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 170: 9)
      - 1994, "Building Peace and Development" (Box-folder 171: 1)
      - 1995, "Confronting New Challenges" (Box-folder 171: 2)
      - 1996 (50th anniversary) (Box-folder 171: 3)
      - 1997, "Renewal Amid Transition" (Box-folder 171: 4)
    - New Dimensions of Arms Regulations and Disarmament in the Post-Cold War Era, report of the Secretary General, 1992 (Box-folder 171: 5)
    - Permanent Missions to the United Nations No. 271, 1992 September (Box-folder 171: 6)
    - "Report of the Independent Working Group on the Future of the United Nations,", 1995 (Box-folder 171: 7)
    - Shelling of UN compound in Qana, 1996 May 1 (Box-folder 171: 8)
  - Security Council
    - "Forecasts (tentative) of the Programme of Work of the Security Council,", 1991-1996
      - 1991 December-1992 December (Box-folder 171: 9)
      - 1993 January-December (Box-folder 172: 1)
      - 1994 January-December (Box-folder 172: 2)
      - 1995 January-December (Box-folder 172: 3)
      - 1996 January-October (Box-folder 172: 4)
    - Provisional verbatim record of Security Council meeting, New York, 1992 January 31 (Box-folder 172: 5)
    - First Security Council meeting at Level of Heads of State or Government (Declaration), clipping, 1992 January 31 (Box-folder 172: 6)
    - Reports to the United Nations Security Council by the Secretary-General
      - 1992 January, July-December (Box-folder 172: 7-8)
      - 1993 (Box-folder 173: 1-3)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 173: 4-6, Box-folder 174: 1)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 174: 2-7)
        Includes draft and final copy of report on peacekeeping operations.
      - 1996 (Box-folder 175: 1-3)
    - Resolution 242, Secretary-General's statement to Palestinian reply, 1992 March (Box-folder 175: 4)
    - Resolutions, various, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 175: 5)
    - Report to Security Council, 1993 January 20 (Box-folder 175: 6)
      Original typescript with notes.
    - Reform, 1994 (Box-folder 175: 7-8)
    - Secretary-General's report on rapid deployment forces (RDF), clipping, 1994 (Box-folder 175: 9)
    - Security Council Summit, 1994 August (Box-folder 175: 10)
    - Resolution of the former Yugoslavia, 1995 (Box-folder 175: 11)
  - Speeches and writings, 1991-1996 (Boxes 175-183)
    See also: Charles Hill Advising and Projects File/"S-G Special" and Papers of Secretary General Boutros Boutros-Ghali/Research Materials.
    - General, 1991-1996
      - List of statements, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 175: 12)
      - List of statements made during trips, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 175: 13)
      - List of statements organized by subject, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 175: 14)
    - Statement to the Third London Conference on Bosnia-Herzegovina, undated (Box-folder 175: 15)
    - Introduction to "Seeds of Partnership,", undated (Box-folder 175: 16)
    - "Development: Clearing Away Old Impediments and Creating a New Rationale,", undated (Box-folder 175: 17)
    - "Réponse à M. Stefan Makowski: Institut für Sufi-Fordererung 'Ce Que Je Crois,' par Boutros Boutros-Ghali,", undated (Box-folder 175: 18)
    - Message of the Secretary-General for publication in the Beijing Review, undated (Box-folder 176: 1)
    - Statement for Welsh television, undated (Box-folder 176: 2)
    - "The United Nations in a New Era," Foreign Affairs, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 176: 3)
      Drafts.
    - Statement, San Salvador, 1992 January 17 (Box-folder 176: 4)
    - "United Nations Peacekeeping in a New Era: A New Chance for Peace,", 1992 January 21 (Box-folder 176: 5)
    - "International Peace-keeping in a Multi-Polar and Multi-Ethnic World,", 1992 May 13 (Box-folder 176: 6)
    - Statement at the Economic and Social Council High Level Segment of Enhancing International Cooperation for Development: The Role of the United Nations, 1992 July 6 (Box-folder 176: 7)
    - "Regional Conflicts: Threat to World Peace and Progress,", 1992 September 9 (Box-folder 176: 8)
    - Address to the Foreign Policy Association, 1992 October 16 (Box-folder 176: 9)
    - United Nations Day concert speech, 1992 October 24 (Box-folder 176: 10)
    - Speech to open Disarmament Week, draft, 1992 October 26 (Box-folder 176: 11)
    - Speech to the 50th Commission of the General Assembly, 1992 November 6 (Box-folder 176: 12)
    - Statement to open "Somalia's Cry: An Exhibition of Photographs,", 1992 November 16 (Box-folder 176: 13)
    - Statement to the Meeting of Tribal Chiefs, Geneva, 1992 December 1 (Box-folder 176: 14)
      Delivered by special representative Sahabzada Yaqub Khan.
    - "Empowering the United Nations," Foreign Affairs, 1992 December (Box-folder 176: 15)
      Physical Description
      Photocopy of printed copy.
    - Draft message from the Secretary-General to the Ministerial Meeting of the Steering Committee of the International Committee on the Former Yugoslavia (UCFY), 1992 December (Box-folder 176: 16)
    - An Agenda for Peace, 1992
      - Contact lists, 1992 (Box-folder 176: 17)
      - Letter from Richard N. Gardner, 1992 August 11 (Box-folder 176: 18)
      - Implementation of An Agenda for Peace, drafts, correspondence, speeches and documents of the Informal Open-Ended Working Group, 1992 October-1993 May (Box-folder 176: 19-21, Box-folder 177: 1-8)
        Also includes meeting minutes and analysis by the UN Security Council.
      - Recommendations, circa 1992 (Box-folder 177: 9)
      - Reactions and progress report, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 178: 1)
      - Printed copies, first edition, 1992 (Box-folder 178: 2-4)
      - Printed copy, second edition, 1995 (Box-folder 178: 5)
    - "United Nations Activities for Africa: The Record of the Past Year," OAU Summit, Cairo, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 178: 6)
    - "Global Development Cooperation,", 1993 (Box-folder 178: 7)
    - "African Development: A New Vision for the 1990s,", 1993 (Box-folder 178: 8)
    - "Beyond Peace-keeping," New York University Conference on the Future of Collective Security, 1993 January 22 (Box-folder 178: 9)
      Includes related talking points and correspondence.
    - "The United Nations: What It Is and What It Can Be,", 1993 March (Box-folder 178: 10)
    - Foreword to "The UN in the Asia-Pacific Region,", 1993 March (Box-folder 178: 11)
    - "Message to the United Nations Association of the USA on the Occasion of the Thirty-Fifth Annual Ball,", 1993 April 21 (Box-folder 178: 12)
    - "The United Nations and the Arab-Israeli Peace Process," Jewish Chronicle, London, typescript draft, 1993 May (Box-folder 178: 13)
    - Letter from the Secretary-General to head of government of the G-7, 1993 May (Box-folder 178: 14)
    - Statement to the United Nations Security Council ministerial session, draft, 1993 May 21 (Box-folder 178: 15)
      Draft by Charles Hill.
    - Video message on the World Conference on Human Rights, draft, 1993 June (Box-folder 178: 16)
    - Opening statement in World Conference on Human Rights, 1993 June (Box-folder 178: 17)
    - "The Foundations of World Progress: A Fresh Look," Kriesky lecture, 1993 June (Box-folder 178: 18)
    - "Multilateralism and Ugly Nationalism,", 1993 August (Box-folder 178: 19)
      Draft.
    - "Multilateralism and the United Nations," New York Times op-ed, 1993 August 16 (Box-folder 178: 20)
    - Statement on United Nations Staff Day, 1993 September 10 (Box-folder 178: 21)
    - "The Establishment of Conduct of United Nations Field Operations," memorandum, 1993 September 27-October 1 (Box-folder 178: 22)
    - "Toast du Secretaire General des Nations Unies à l'occasion du dîner de la francophonie offert par le ministre des affaires etrangères de la republique Française,", 1993 October 1 (Box-folder 178: 23)
    - Statement to the United Nations Association of the United States (UNA-USA), 1993 October 29 (Box-folder 178: 24)
    - Binder of speeches from visit to Japan, the Korean peninsula, and China, 1993 December (Box-folder 179: 1)
    - Meeting with the Foreign Affairs Committee of the Bundestag of the Federal Republic of Germany, 1994 January 18 (Box-folder 179: 2)
    - Gabriel Silver memorial lecture, Columbia University, 1994 February (Box-folder 179: 3)
    - Address of the Secretary-General to the Joint Meeting of the Group on Equal Rights for Women in the United Nations and the Women's Environment and Development Organization on the Occasion of International Women's Day, 1994 March 8 (Box-folder 179: 4)
    - "The United Nations - An Agenda for the 21st Century,", 1994 June 8 (Box-folder 179: 5)
    - Address to the First Committee, 1994 October 17 (Box-folder 179: 6)
    - "The UN and Democracy," 1994 Gauer Distinguished Lecture in Law and Public Policy of the National Legal Center for the Public Interest, New York, 1994 October 18 (Box-folder 179: 7)
    - Address to the Ministerial Segment, United Nations International Symposium on Trade Efficiency, 1994 October 19 (Box-folder 179: 8)
    - Toast for the United Nations Symposium on Trade Efficiency, Columbus, Ohio, 1994 October 19 (Box-folder 179: 9)
    - Address to the Ministerial Segment of the United Nations International Symposium on Trade Efficiency, Columbus, Ohio, 1994 October 19 (Box-folder 179: 10)
    - "Creating a World in Balance: The World Summit on Social Development,", 1994 October 21 (Box-folder 179: 11)
    - "Message to the People of South Africa on United Nations Day 1994,", 1994 October 24 (Box-folder 179: 12)
    - Opening statement, The Diplomatic and Commonwealth Writers' Association, 1994 October 24 (Box-folder 179: 13)
    - Message for United Nations Day, 1994 October 24 (Box-folder 179: 14)
    - Message on World AIDS Day 1994, 1994 December 1 (Box-folder 179: 15)
    - An Agenda for Development, 1995
      - General, UN development, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 179: 16)
      - Op-ed on development, notes, 1992 October (Box-folder 179: 17)
      - "Organizing and Coordinating for Development: Documents for the Secretary-General's remarks to Rio follow up,", 1992 November 2 (Box-folder 179: 18)
      - Note and draft outlines, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 179: 19-20)
      - Drafts and research materials, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 179: 21)
      - Draft, 1994 May 8 (Box-folder 179: 22)
      - Draft and comments, 1994 (Box-folder 180: 1)
      - Recommendations, 1994 (Box-folder 180: 2-3)
      - Printed copy, 1995 (Box-folder 180: 4)
      - Printed copy (photocopy), 1995 (Box-folder 180: 5)
    - Statements on peacekeeping, 1994 September-1995 April (Box-folder 180: 6)
    - "Statement on the occasion of the death of Bosnian Foreign Minister Dr. Irfan Ljubijankic,", 1995 (Box-folder 180: 7)
    - "The Charter at the Opening of Its Second Half-Century,", 1995 (Box-folder 180: 8)
    - "A New Departure for Development,", 1995 (Box-folder 180: 9)
    - "Supplement to an Agenda for Peace: Position Paper of the Secretary-General on the Occasion of the Fiftieth Anniversary of the United Nations," report to UN Security Council, 1995 January 3 (Box-folder 180: 10)
    - Binder of speeches from visit to Finland, Sweden, Denmark, Germany, and Switzerland, 1995 January 10-26 (Box-folder 180: 11)
    - Visit to the UNU/World Institute for Development Economics Research, Helsinki, 1995 January 11 (Box-folder 180: 12)
    - Visit to the Office of the World Health Organization, 1995 January 16 (Box-folder 180: 13)
    - "Remarks on Receiving the Charter of the United Nations from the United States National Archives,", 1995 February 1 (Box-folder 180: 14)
    - Statement to the World Summit for Social Development, draft, 1995 February 6 (Box-folder 180: 15)